Guide to the Carl Cunningham papers, 1965-2017 MS 888
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Carl Cunningham papers
1965-2017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Cunningham, Carl
MS 888
7 Linear Feet 7 boxes
The collection consists mainly of programs for which Carl Cunningham wrote commentary. The materials are in good condition, and range in date from 1965 to 2017.
Biographical / Historical
Carl Robert Cunningham (1931- ), a California native, holds degrees from Notre Dame and the University of Southern California. After serving in the Navy, he taught music and was a choir director in Honolulu, 1959-63. He was music critic for the San Francisco Chronicle before settling in Houston, where he was music editor of the Houston Post, 1966-1995, and was on the University of St. Thomas faculty, 1968-1986. With others, he wrote a history of Houston Grand Opera (2005) and has long composed program notes and liner notes for many classical music ensembles and dance troupes around the United States, including the Houston Symphony and Houston Grand Opera.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists mainly of programs for which Carl Cunningham wrote commentary. The materials are in good condition, and range in date from 1965 to 2017.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in eight series as follows: Series I: Personal Papers; Series II: Symphony Programs; Series III: Music Festival Programs; Series IV: Classical Music Programs; Series V: Ballet; Series VI: Houston Vocal Groups; Series VII: Opera; Series VIII: Addendum
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were donated by Carl Cunningham in May 2017.
Index Terms
Subjects
Music; Performing arts; Social life and customs
Document Types
programs (documents); theses
- Series I: Personal Papers
  - Carl Cunningham M.A. thesis (typescript), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Symphony Programs
  - Austin Symphony, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Austin Symphony, Jan.-May 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Austin Symphony, Sept.-Dec. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Austin Symphony, Jan.-Apr. 1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Austin Symphony, Sept.-Dec. 1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Austin Symphony, Feb.-May 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Toronto Symphony, Oct. 1996, May 1997, June 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Detroit Symphony, Feb. 1998-June 2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Detroit Symphony, Oct. 2000-June 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Detroit Symphony, Mar.-June 2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Detroit Symphony, Mar.-May 2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Detroit Symphony, Sept. 2003-May 2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Detroit Symphony, Oct.-Nov. 2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Orpheus Chamber Orchestra (NY), 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Orpheus Chamber Orchestra (NY), 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Orpheus Chamber Orchestra (NY), 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Orpheus Chamber Orchestra (NY), 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Orpheus Chamber Orchestra (NY), 2001-2003 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Orpheus Chamber Orchestra (NY), 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Houston Symphony Chamber Players, 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Houston Symphony programs (bound), 1996-2003 (Box 2)
  - Houston Symphony programs (bound), 2003-2011 (Box 3)
- Series III: Music Festival Programs
  - Texas Music Festival, 2015-2017 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Spoleto Festival, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Spoleto Festival, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Spoleto Festival, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Spoleto Festival, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Spoleto Festival, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Spoleto Festival, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Series IV: Classical Music Groups
  - Steinway Society (CA), 2006 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Steinway Society (CA), 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Steinway Society (CA), 2008-2009 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Steinway Society (CA), 2009-2010 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Steinway Society (CA), 2010-2011 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Steinway Society (CA), 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Steinway Society (CA), 2012-2013 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cliburn Concerts (TX), 2012-2014 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Cliburn Concerts (TX), 2015-2017 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Da Camera of Houston, 1996-2000 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Da Camera of Houston, 2003-2006 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Da Camera of Houston, 2006-2008 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Da Camera of Houston, 2008-2010 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Da Camera of Houston, 2010-2012 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Da Camera of Houston, 2012-2017 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Indianapolis Symphonic Choir, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Series V: Ballet
  - Houston Ballet, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Houston Ballet, 1998, 2004, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Houston Ballet, 2007-2009, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Santa Fe Festival Ballet, Ballet Pro Musica, 1999, 2005-2007 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Ballet Theatre of Maryland, 2002-2003 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - International Ballet of Mexico, 2009-2013 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Houston Vocal Groups
  - Houston Masterworks Chorus, 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Houston Chamber Choir, 1996-2000 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Houston Chamber Choir, 2001-2007 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Houston Chamber Choir, 2008-2011 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Houston Chamber Choir, 2011-2012 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Houston Chamber Choir, 2012-2013 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Houston Chamber Choir, 2013-2014 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Houston Chamber Choir, 2014-2015 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Houston Chamber Choir, 2015-2016 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Houston Chamber Choir, 2016-2017 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Series VII: Opera
  - Houston Grand Opera, 1968, 1989, 1996-2000 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Houston Grand Opera, 2004-2006 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Houston Grand Opera, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Houston Grand Opera, 2011-2014 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Dallas Opera, Minn. Opera, Lyric Opera, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Los Angeles Opera, San Francisco Opera, 1996, 1998, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Santa Fe Opera, 1996, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Santa Fe Opera, 2000-2005 (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Series VIII: Addendum
  - Sub-series A: Articles
    - Carl Cunningham Biographical Profile, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "Houston Ballet: A Historical Sketch" by Carl Cunningham (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - List of people interviewed for Carl Cunningham's book (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Newsprint, 1981-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Sub-series B: Performance Reviews
    - American Record Guide: Concert, Opera Reviews, 1995, 1998, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - American Record Guide: Concert, Opera Reviews, September/October 2003, March/April 2005 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - American Record Guide: Concert, Opera Reviews, May/June 2005, March/April 2007 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - S.P.A. Programs and Reviews, 2000-2009 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - S.P.A Programs and Reviews, 2010-2016 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - (Various) Performance Reviews, 1995-2012 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - (Various) Publications in Opera News, Reviews (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series C: Cassette Tapes
    - Almeida, Antonio de, 1986-08-12 (Box 7)
    - Atherhoit (Box 7)
    - Barbirolli, Lady (Jones Hall), 1986-08-15 (Box 7)
    - Barbirolli, Lady II, 1986-08-15 (Box 7)
    - Ben-Dor, Gisele, 1989-06 (Box 7)
    - Black, Bill I, 1987-09-29 (Box 7)
    - Black, Bill II, 1987-09-29 (Box 7)
    - Black, WIlliam / Foster, Lawrence, 1990-08-14 (Box 7)
    - Black, WIlliam / Lawrence Foster II, 1990-08-14 (Box 7)
    - Cater, John T., 1991-08-26 (Box 7)
    - Clay, Orson, 1992-03-26 (Box 7)
    - Commisiona, Sergiu, 1985-02-26 (Box 7)
    - Commisiona, Sergiu, 1987-06 (Box 7)
    - Commisiona, Sergiu III, 1989-08-18 (Box 7)
    - Crouse, Wayne, 1987-08-08 (Box 7)
    - Crouse, Wayne II, 1987-08-08 (Box 7)
    - Elliott, Tom, Tape 1, 1991-09-10 (Box 7)
    - Elliott, Tom, Tape II, 1991-09-10 (Box 7)
    - Eschenbach (1989-1990 season), 1989-02-13 (Box 7)
    - Eschenbach, Cristoph, 1988-08-17 (Box 7)
    - Eschenbach, Cristoph, 1989-07-21 (Box 7)
    - Eschenbach, Cristoph, 1990-02 (Box 7)
    - Eschenbach, Cristoph, 1990-04-23 (Box 7)
    - Eschenbach, Cristoph, 1990-07-27 (Box 7)
    - Eschenbach, Cristoph, 1991-12-03 (Box 7)
    - Eschenbach: Final intv, 2000-02-05 (Box 7)
    - Fliegel, Raphael, 50th Anniversary, 1987-05 (Box 7)
    - Fliegel, Ray / Previn, 1987-08-17 (Box 7)
    - Fliegel, Ray / Previn II, 1987-08-17 (Box 7)
    - Fliegel, Raphael / Foster, Harwood Comissiona, 1989-09-01 (Box 7)
    - Fliegel, Raphael / Eschenbach, 1991-08-28 (Box 7)
    - Foster, Lawrence, 1986-03 (Box 7)
    - Foster, Lawrence, 1988-08-11 (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Tom (Foster), Summer, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Gutierrez, Horacio, 1986-09 (Box 7)
    - Horrocks, Jim, 1991-08-21 (Box 7)
    - HSO News Conference: Contract with Virgin Classics, 1990-07-26 (Box 7)
    - Janowski, Judy, 1992-07-07 (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Dolores I, 1990-08-25 (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Dolores III, 1990-08-25 (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Tom M. / Barbirolli (Jones Hall), 1986-08-22 (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Tom / Andre Previn, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Tom / Previn / Almeida, 1987-08-18 (Box 7)
    - KRTS Symphony In Singapore 12 Reports, n.d. (Box 7)
    - Levine, Max, 1989-08-29 (Box 7)
    - Martin, Neil (1/3), 1992-11-12 (Box 7)
    - Martin, Neil (3/3), 1992-11-12 (Box 7)
    - Medvitz, Jim I, 1990-11-23 (Box 7)
    - Medvitz, Jim III, 1990-11-23 (Box 7)
    - Merrill, Richard I, 1992-12-27 (Box 7)
    - Mitchell, George, 1992-03-24 (Box 7)
    - Mitchell, George (Woodlands) (Box 7)
    - Neumann, Selma, I, 1990-08-15 (Box 7)
    - Patterson, Ronald / Foster, et al., 1991-08-31 (Box 7)
    - Picker, Tobias, 2007-03-14 (Box 7)
    - Previn, Andre / Kent Hackleman, 1969-05 (Box 7)
    - Previn, Andre, 1987-01-19 (Box 7)
    - Previn, Andre, 1987-01-19 (Box 7)
    - Schofer, Marvin / Comissiona, 1987-02-26 (Box 7)
    - Silverstein, Joseph, 1990-07-29 (Box 7)
    - Sipser, Philip, 1992-07-09 (Box 7)
    - Stein, Stephen (Los Angeles) I, 2007-10-12 (Box 7)
    - Stein, Stephen II, 2007-10-12 (Box 7)
    - Takaro, Tom (library), 2013-03-14 (Box 7)
    - Tippett Press Conference, 1989-09-27 (Box 7)
    - Toeplitz, Gideon I, 1987-07-30 (Box 7)
    - Toeplitz, Gideon, 1987-07-30 (Box 7)
    - Van Besian, Matthew, 2009-12-08 (Box 7)
    - Wax, David, 2000-07-27 (Box 7)
    - Wax, David II, 2000-07-28 (Box 7)
    - Wax, David III, 2000-07-28 (Box 7)
    - Waters, David / Barbirolli - Previn, 1987-08-24 (Box 7)
    - Waters, Devid / Barbirolli, Previn, 1987-08-24 (Box 7)
    - Wayland, Newton, 1993-05 (Box 7)
    - Welch, Louie I, 1989-08-07 (Box 7)
    - Will, Jim, 1995-05-06 (Box 7)
    - Wilson, Marian, 1992-09-28 (Box 7)
    - Woolcock, Michael I, 1991-10-22 (Box 7)
    - Woolcock, Michael II, 1991-10-22 (Box 7)
    - Woolcock, Michael III, 1991-10-22 (Box 7)
    - Wright, Jim / Santa Barbara, 1991-07-30 (Box 7)
    - Wright, Jim / Santa Barbara II, 1991-07-30 (Box 7)